Sofiyullahi Jamiu

Software Engineer



PROFILE

Mission-driven full-stack Software Developer with 6+ years of experience in web development, algorithms, software testing, and database management with the goal of offering top-quality service/experience by providing optimal software solutions and increasing business efficiency while delivering world-class results as smoothly as possible.

SE CONTACT

A	B7 4RF Compass, Bimingham, UK
C	+44 740 325 4257
\times	sofiyullahj@gmail.com
#	https://sofiyullahj.dev



్రే SKILLS & TOOLS

REACT **VS CODE JAVASCRIPT FIGMA** NODEJS CHROME REMOTE DESKTOP HTML & CSS ZOOM DATABASE MANAGEMENT **GITHUB**

FIREBASE

GIT/SOURCE CONTROL

NEXTJS

REDUX

WEB HOSTING/APP DEPLOYMENT

API



A LANGUAGES

ENGLISH













Games

Music

Football Designing













EDUCATION

Birmingham City University - Birmingham, UK

- · Master of User Experience Design
- 2022 present

University of Ilorin - Ilorin, Nigeria

- · Bachelor of Computer Science
- 2014 2018



EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Software Engineer

Emjay Information Technology(via codementor), Lagos, Jun. 2021 - present

- Successfully completed over 1500 coding sessions for various clients, ranging from startups to established businesses.
- Collaborated closely with clients to collect requirements, provide technical direction, and ensure project objectives were met within the specified time frame.
- Delivered maintainable solutions by utilizing best practices such as version control, code reviews, and testing.
- Participated in team meetings to exchange ideas, learn, and enhance development processes.

Fullstack Software Engineer

UNPLUGDD, Lagos. Apr. 2019 - Jun. 2021

- · Developed a user-friendly and lightning-fast user interface.
- Helped backend engineers understand frontend components, their purpose, and how to integrate them best.
- I helped integrate a messaging system that lets people chat while watching live events to make it more entertaining and realistic.
- I worked with the team to build/integrate an automated 24/7 live support system for users.
- Created scalable and user-friendly solutions using technologies such as nextJS, redux, typescript, nodeJS etc.

Frontend Engineer

Agape, Lagos. May 2018 - Mar. 2019

- · Collaborated with developers from different parts of the world to assist them fix bugs and complete coding tasks/challenges.
- Mentored and provided guidance for new and aspiring web developers.
- Participated in developer-oriented social events to network with peers from across the world, share insights on how to improve the user experience, and learn about the latest trends in Web development.